生活大爆炸
第四季第二十四集[本季终]
Hey, you guys ready to order?
你们想好点啥菜了吗
- Uh, sure. - Okay, Priya?
-想好了  -好的  普丽娅
Uh, I'll have the shepherd's pie.
我来一份肉馅土豆泥饼
You want to split that with me?
你想和我分着吃一份吗
Oh, no, no, no, he doesn't.
别别别  他不会愿意的
Why not?
为啥
Well, you have milk in the taters,
土豆泥里面有牛奶
milk in the gravy, parmesan crust.
肉汁里面有牛奶  还有帕尔玛干酪饼皮
Your lactose-intolerant boyfriend will turn
你这位乳糖不耐的男朋友会变成
into a gas-filled Macy's Day balloon.
一个充气的感恩节大气球
Not quite accurate.
你说的不全对
The Macy's balloons are filled with helium,
感恩节气球里充的都是氦气
whereas Leonard produces copious amounts of methane.
而莱纳德肚子里造出来的是大量的甲烷
So, no, on the shepherd's pie.
所以  还是别点肉馅土豆泥饼了
Can we move on?
能接着点菜吗
Yeah, a little tip: he says he can eat frozen yogurt.
行  再给一条小贴士  他说自己能吃冻酸奶
Do not believe it.
千万别信
Sea bass! I'll have the sea bass!
海鲈  我想来份海鲈
You gotta like this,
你得习惯啊
the girlfriend and the ex-girlfriend bonding
现任女友和前任女友通过
over your rooty-tooty stinky booty.
聊你的糗事来联络感情
Kill me.
杀了我吧
It wouldn't help. The human body is capable
没用的  人体能在死亡数小时内
of being flatulent for hours after death.
一直制造气体
Guys, sorry I'm late.
各位  抱歉来晚了
I have amazing news.
我有个好消息
Bernadette, before you change the subject,
伯纳黛特  在你换话题之前
does anyone have any final comments on
有人想对莱纳德糟糕的消化系统
Leonard's faulty digestive system?
来个终极吐槽吗
So, what's your news, Bernadette?
啥好消息啊  伯纳黛特
The thesis committee accepted my doctoral dissertation.
论文委员会接受了我的博士论文
I'm getting my PhD!
我拿到博士学位了
Wow! Oh, congratulations.
哇  恭喜恭喜
Wow, so that means you're a doctor, you're a doctor,
哇  这就意味着你是博士  你是博士
you're a doctor, you're a doctor,
你也是博士  你还是博士
and Howard, you know a lot of doctors.
而霍华德  你认识不少博士啊
Congratulations, honey.
祝贺你呀  亲爱的
Thank you.
谢谢
So, Howard, tell us, how's it feel knowing
霍华德  跟我们说说当你得知
that when you two get married,
等你俩结婚了  大家得叫你们
you'll be referred to as Mr. and Dr. Wolowitz?
沃罗威茨先生和沃罗威茨博士  你作何感想
Unless he takes Bernadette's last name.
除非他能随伯纳黛特的姓
And considering her advanced status,
考虑到伯纳黛特的地位更高
that could open some doors for him.
这么做未尝不可
Please, this isn't about me.
拜托  今天的主角不是我
I'm proud of you.
我真为你骄傲
Well, you'll be really be proud of this.
还有更让你骄傲的呢
I was headhunted by a big pharmaceutical company.
我被一家大型医药公司看中了
They're gonna pay me a buttload of money!
他们要给我提供巨额薪金
What?
什么
Bernadette, that's great.
伯纳黛特  这太好了
Howard, do you make a buttload?
霍华德  你能挣巨额的钱吗
Better than what you've got a buttload of.
反正比你放巨额的屁强
Hey, if I roll down the windows in the car, everything's peachy.
喂  要是我摇下车窗玻璃  一切都还是很美好的
If you do it, you're still not a doctor.
可如果你也这么做  你还是当不了博士
Yeah, just a heads-up on the car window deal.
嗯  车窗户这这句我得吐个槽
It helps, but everything is not "peachy."
虽然说得对  但不是每件事都那么美好
（嘻哈歌曲《Ice Ice baby》）
*Oh, if there was a problem, you can't solve it
如果你有问题  你又不能解决*
*Check out the hook while my DJ revolves it
接受这诱惑  让我的DJ来解决*
*Ice, Ice, baby
冰  冰  宝贝*
Oh, God, I feel ridiculous in this dress.
天啊  我觉得穿着这件衣服显得好傻啊
You look beautiful, Lieutenant Uhura.
你看起来美极了  乌胡拉少尉
Now prepare for... inspection.
那现在开始准备  检查
Shh, my brother's going to hear you.
嘘  别让我哥听见了
Relax, he's got headphones on.
放心吧  他带着耳机呢
And we're ten miles above Earth in a starship.
而我们正在距地球16公里远的星际飞船里呢
Really, ten miles?
开玩笑吧  才16公里
（地球大气的平均厚度约为1000公里）
You're orbiting inside the atmosphere?
还在大气层里转悠啊
Moron.
脑残
I can't believe I'm wearing my brother's Halloween costume.
我真不敢相信我在穿我哥的万圣节化妆服
I can't believe you think he only wears it on Halloween.
我真不敢相信你真以为他只在万圣节的时候穿
Open the landing bay doors, shuttle craft approaching.
打开"降落舱门"  "航天飞机"正在进入
Okay, gotta go.
好吧  我得撤了
Hey, what's up?
嗨  怎么了
Is that my future daughter-in-law, the doctor?!
是我未来的儿媳博士来了吗
No, Ma! It's Raj!
不是  妈  是拉杰
- He's a doctor too, right?! - Yes!
-他也是博士  对吗  -对
Like Leonard and the skinny weirdo!
跟莱纳德和那个竹竿子一样
Sheldon, yes!
那是谢尔顿  没错
Everybody's a doctor but me!
除了我  大家都是博士
Well, whose fault is that?!
那能怪谁呢
What's up?
怎么了
Leonard's putting disgusting memories in
莱纳德在我的记忆海绵床垫上
my memory foam mattress.
制造恶心的记忆
Can I stay here tonight?
我今晚能睡你这儿吗
Sure, but I'm going out with Bernadette.
行  但我要去见伯纳黛特
It'll just be you and my mother.
所以就你和我妈在家
I guess that's okay.
我猜应该没事吧
Ma, can Rajesh sleep over?!
妈  拉杰能睡这儿吗
Of course, he and I can play doctor!
行啊  他可以和我玩扮医生的游戏[doctor也有医生的意思]
She's kidding, right?
她在开玩笑  对吧
I don't know, she's pretty feisty since
我不知道  自从接受荷尔蒙替换治疗之后
they put her on hormone-replacement therapy.
她就变得精力充沛了
Paging Dr. Cutie Pie!
呼叫小可爱医生
I must say, Amy, I was very impressed
我不得不说  艾米  我对于
to see that Bernadette got her PhD.
伯纳黛特拿到博士学位感到非常惊讶
It's indeed admirable.
确实令人钦佩
Although, it is... microbiology.
虽然  她是搞  微生物学的
Your doctorate is in neurobiology.
你的博士学位是神经生物学的
I fail to see the distinction.
我看不出什么差别
I'll make it simple for you.
我就这么跟你说吧
I study the brain,
我研究的是大脑
the organ responsible for Beethoven's Fifth Symphony.
这是能让贝多芬写出《命运交响曲》的器官
Bernadette studies yeast,
而伯纳黛特研究的是酵母菌
the organism responsible for Michelob Lite.
是用来制造Michelob Lite啤酒的有机体
Is there something wrong with your neck?
你的脖子不舒服吗
It's a little stiff.
有点僵硬
What a remarkably fragile structure
如此不堪一击的结构
to support such a valuable payload.
却要支撑如此价值连城的设备
Not unlike balancing a Faberge egg on a Pixie Stick.
这无异于用精灵粉末糖来支撑皇室珠宝彩蛋
Have you considered massage?
你考虑过做个按摩吗
I'd like to respond to that sarcastically:
我想用讽刺的口吻来回答你的问题
Yes, I relish the thought of a stranger covering my body
是的  让一个陌生人给我的身体涂油并按压
with oil and rubbing it.
这个想法很不错
I was proposing you massage your muscles with your own hands.
我是建议你亲手对自己的肌肉进行按摩
Still sounds like a lot of unnecessary touching.
那还是会涉及到很多不必要的触碰
Trust me.
相信我
With your right hand,
伸出你的右手
locate the spot where the scapula meets the acromion process.
找到肩胛骨和肩峰的交界处
All right.
好了
Now push your third finger along the ridge of the shoulder blade,
然后用右手中指沿肩胛的突起进行按压
making a small rotation as you do so.
同时小幅度揉动
Rotating.
揉着呢
You should feel a small node-like object
你应该能感觉到有一个突起的结构
rolling back and forth along the bone.
在沿着骨头前后滚动
You mean the myofascial point?
你是指肌筋膜点吗
Obviously.
不然呢
Now bear down on it
接着向其施力
like the seventh grade noogies
就像我们熟悉的七年级生
we all know too well.
欺负人用的经典按头动作
Oh, dear Lord, yes, yes, oh, yes!
额滴神啊  爽  爽  爽
Amy, I've never been touched like this before!
艾米  以前从来没人这么摸过我
Oh! My hands are magic!
我的手简直是神来之手啊
Don't flatter yourself.
别自吹自擂了
Your hands are blunt tools guided by my knowledge
你的手不过是在本人神经系统知识指导下的
of the nervous system.
一个愚钝的工具而已
I could just as easily have paralyzed you.
我刚也可以轻易地让你瘫痪
There's someone at my door.
有人在敲门
That doesn't interest me. Good-bye.
我对此不感兴趣  拜拜
- Can I sleep here tonight? - Why?
-我能在这里过夜吗  -凭什么
Leonard's having astronomically inaccurate
莱纳德正和我妹妹进行星际迷航式的性交
Star Trek sex with my sister.
那从天文学角度来说很不科学
I can see how that would be upsetting. Come in.
的确很令人心烦意乱  进来吧
I'll get the sheets and blankets for the couch.
我去拿铺在沙发上的床单和毯子
Oh, don't bother. I'll just sleep in Leonard's room.
不用了  我去莱纳德的房间睡就行
No, I can't authorize that.
不行  我不能授权
Well, he's in my bed. Why can't I be in his?
他能睡在我床上  我为啥不能睡在他床上
The Hammurabic Code is "an eye for an eye,"
汉谟拉比法典上规定可以"以眼还眼"
not "a bed for a bed."
而并非"以床还床"
Come on, dude, I'm exhausted,
行行好  哥们  我快累死了
and Tyra Banks says
提拉·班克斯说过
（提拉·班克斯  美国著名模特）
the most important item in your makeup bag
化妆包里最重要的一样东西
is a good night's sleep.
就是夜晚香甜的睡眠
All right.
好吧
This is a form indemnifying me
要想使用"莱纳德的卧室"
from your use of "Leonard's bedroom."
需要先签署这张我的免责表
Sign here, indicating that I tried to stop you
在这里签字  说明我试图阻止过你
and did so using a stern facial expression.
并摆出过严厉的面部表情
- Good night, Sheldon.  - Wait. Not yet.
-晚安  谢尔顿  -等等  还没完
We still have to go over safety procedures.
我们还要重温一下安全规程
Now, the apartment has three emergency exits located
这间公寓里共有三个紧急出口  分别在
here, here, and here.
这里  这里和这里
In the event of a power outage,
万一遇到停电事故
luminous paint will guide you to the nearest exit.
夜光漆可指引你从最近的出口逃生
You're kidding.
开玩笑吧你
I never kid about safety.
在安全问题上  我从不儿戏
What are you doing here?
你在我房间里干什么
I was sleeping.
睡觉啊
In my bed?
在我床上
Well, I would've slept in my own bed,
我也想睡在自己的床上
but it was being used to bring shame to my family.
但它却用来给我的家庭带来耻辱
And the memory of Gene Roddenberry.
还让我想起来了吉恩·罗登贝瑞
（吉恩·罗登贝瑞  《星际迷航》中的演员）
Oh, you heard?
你听见了吗
"Scotty, I need more power."
"史考特  我需要更多的能量"
Sorry. Does Sheldon know you're sleeping in here?
抱歉  谢尔顿知道你睡在这里吗
Are you kidding? He made me sign a waiver,
怎么可能不知道  他逼我签了免责书
participate in an emergency fire drill
参加了紧急消防演习
and take a refresher course in CPR.
还复习了心脏复苏术的课程
Thank God he had a dummy.
还好他有个人体模型
Oh, yeah. Mouth-to-Mouth Mona.
是啊  嘴对嘴的莫娜
You know, she used to date Howard?
知道吗  她和霍华德谈过恋爱
Oh, my God, she's that Mona?
天啊  她就是那个莫娜吗
Why can't you and my sister spend your nights here?
你和我妹妹为什么不能在这里共度春宵呢
We tried. She doesn't get along with Sheldon.
我们试过  但是她和谢尔顿合不来
Sheldon doesn't get along with Sheldon.
谢尔顿跟他自己都合不来
It's still no reason for me to have to listen to you
但那也不足以说服我听你的话
arm your photon torpedoes every night.
每晚都要装备上光子鱼雷
Okay, well, how about this:
好吧  不如这样
until Priya gets her own place,
在普丽娅找到自己的住处之前
you stay here and I'll stay at your apartment.
你住在这里  而我住在你家
Can I bring girls here?
我能带女孩过来吗
You?
就凭你
Sure. Bring as many as you want.
当然了  想带多少带多少
Okay, deal.
好的  就这么定了
Just not against their will.
别强迫她们就行了
You really think you should be eating that cake?
你觉得吃那块蛋糕合适吗
Why?
怎么了
If you're gonna be a trophy husband for a rich wife,
鉴于你即将成为富婆的小白脸老公
you might want to watch your waistline.
你可要注意自己的腰围啊
He's right.
他说得对
A minute on the lips, a lifetime on the hips.
嘴上一时享受  臀上一世肥肉
Yeah, ha-ha.
是啊  真幽默
First of all, I'm not threatened by my fiance's success.
首先  我未婚妻的成功并没对我造成威胁
I'm proud of her.
我为她感到骄傲
And secondly, I have my own career.
其次  我拥有自己的事业
Until you have kids.
有了孩子可就不一样了
Good news, Raj.
好消息  拉杰
I got the blood work back from the lab.
我刚从实验室取回了你的血样报告
You're okay to stay for a while.
你可以在我家待上一段时间了
When did you take my blood?
你什么时候帮我抽的血
Not important.
这不重要
Your sugar was a little high.
你血糖有点偏高
I'd follow up with your regular physician.
我会跟你医生保持联系的
In the meantime, I have some paperwork here
同时  这里还有些文件
for you to go over.
要请你过目
What the hell is this?
这又是什么东东
Boilerplate stuff.
都是些陈辞滥调啦
A modified roommate agreement for a temporary house guest.
针对临时住客的改良版室友协议
And a living will and durable power of attorney.
还有生前遗嘱和永久委托书
This says you can make "end of life" decisions for me.
这里说你可以帮我决定生命终止与否
As your friend, let's hope it doesn't come to that.
作为朋友  希望事不至此
Please sign.
签名吧
Did you sign this?
你签过这个吗
There's a reciprocity clause.
上面有互惠条款
You get to pull the plug on him, too.
你也可以终结他的
Well, that seems fair.
好吧  这样挺公平
Congratulations and welcome temporarily aboard.
恭喜了  欢迎暂时入住
Here's your I.D. card,
这是你的ID卡
your key and your lapel pin.
钥匙和胸牌
Which Leonard was too cool to wear.
莱纳德居然觉得这胸牌配不上他
FYI, part of your responsibilities as roommate pro tem
还有  作为临时室友的部分职责
will be to drive me to and from work,
是送我上下班
the comic book store, the barbershop
送我去漫画书店  理发店
and the park for one hour every other Sunday for fresh air.
隔周周日送我去公园呼吸新鲜空气
Bring a ball or a Frisbee,
带上个球或飞盘
you know, something he can chase.
好让他去接
Also, you're tasked with bringing home all takeout dinners.
还有  所有的外卖都由你负责帮我带
Tonight is Thai food.
今晚是泰国菜
You'll find the standard order in appendix B
标准点菜订单在附录B
or downloadable from my FTP server.
或可从我的FTP下载
If you have any questions,
如有任何问题
here's the FAQ sheet,
这里列出了常见问题的答案
or if you prefer the human touch,
若你更喜欢人性化解答
I do a live web chat called "Apartment Talk" on Tuesday nights
每周四晚我提供公寓问题的在线聊天服务
No backsies.
不许反悔哦
Sheldon, dinner!
谢尔顿  吃晚餐了
What is this?
这是什么
This is the difference between eating and dining.
这就是单纯吃饭与用餐的区别
Remarkable. I'm just realizing how much
太了不起了  我这才意识到
Leonard's been skating by all these years.
莱纳德这么些年一直有多敷衍
It's not a big thing.
没什么大不了的
（玛莎·斯图尔特  美国家政女王  主妇界的偶像）
Just think of me as a brown Martha Stewart.
就把我看成棕色版的玛莎·斯图尔特吧
Hey, Sheldon,
嗨  谢尔顿
did you change your Wi-Fi password again?
你是不是又改了无线上网密码
Yes, it's "Penny, get your own Wi-Fi." No spaces.
对  现在是"佩妮自己去开无线上网"  没有空格
Thanks.
多谢
What's with the fancy spread?
这一大桌好料是怎么回事
My new roommate is bending over backwards
这是我的新室友在不遗余力地
to ingratiate himself to me.
迎合讨好我
Uh, nice touch, by the way.
顺便说  胸牌别的好
What do you mean "new roommate"? What happened to Leonard?
什么"新室友"  莱纳德怎么了
The same thing that happened to Homo erectus.
跟直立人一样
He was replaced by a superior species.
被更高级物种取代了
I'm the new Homo in town.
我是这家新新人[我是新的同性恋]
That came out wrong.
那是口误
All right, let me try this again. Where's Leonard?
好吧  这么问吧  莱纳德在哪
He's living at my place, so I'm living here.
他住在我公寓  所以我住这来了
You're living here provisionally.
你目前只是暂时住这
But I must say it's looking good.
但我必须说  你干得不错
Leonard and Priya are living together?
莱纳德和普丽娅同居了
That's big.
这可是大事啊
No. Origami napkin swans...
不  手工折的餐巾天鹅
that's the headline.
这才是大事
It's a good thing.
而且是好事
So do you know what kind of research you'll be doing
你知道在这个制药厂  你将从事
at this pharmaceutical company?
哪方面的研究吗
Well, there are a couple of opportunities available,
有很多种选择
but I volunteered for the premature ejaculation project.
但我自愿参加了早泄问题研究
I mean, it's not like either one of us has heart disease.
反正我们俩都没有心脏病
Oh, I almost forgot. I got you a little present.
差点忘了  我给你买了个小礼物
Oh, Bernie, no. You didn't have to.
妮妮  你不用这样的
I wanted to. Come on, open it.
我想给你买嘛  来  打开看看
You bought me a Rolex?
你给我买了块劳力士手表
How much did this cost?
这得多少钱啊
Oh, you let me worry about the money.
让我来操心赚钱的事吧
I just want my baby to have pretty things.
我只想我的宝贝拥有漂亮东西
More wine?
再来点酒吗
Oh, no, no, no. I've had way too much already.
不不不  我已经高了
Here's an interesting fact about alcohol...
关于酒  有个很有趣的事...
Hit me.
再给我满上
Man is not the only species
人类并不是唯一一个
that ferments fruit in order to become intoxicated.
会发酵水果酿酒的物种
Can you guess what the other is?
能猜到还有哪个物种也会吗
Hint: sometimes they pack the alcohol in their trunks.
提示  有时他们会把酒装进旅行箱[trunk也有象鼻的意思]
Monkeys.
猴子
When does a monkey have a trunk?
猴子什么时候有旅行箱了
When a suitcase just won't do.
当手提箱太小装不下酒时
Mmm, all right.
好吧
It would appear as if alcohol
很快就知道酒精是不是
is playing keep-away with your intelligence.
正在将你的智力一步步夺走
Good night.
晚安
Please note, it is now past 10:00 p.m.
请记住  已经10点多了
Per our roommate agreement, kindly refrain
根据我们的室友协议  请好心避免
from raucous laughter,
刺耳的笑声
clinking of glasses, and celebratory gunfire.
玻璃的叮当声和庆祝的炮火声
Okay...
好吧
explain something to me.
请教一下
You watch Leonard put up with that guy for years and years.
你眼睁睁看着莱纳德忍受他一年又一年
What has to break inside your brain for you to think,
你脑子里哪根筋搭错  让你觉得
"Oh, Krishna, I've got to get me some of that"?
"克利须那神  我也想被折磨一把"
Well, it's a lot better than having
这比在自家公寓
to wear noise-cancelling headphones in my own apartment.
戴着消音耳机强多了
What? Oh, God, yeah. Yeah.
什么  天啊  我懂我懂
Leonard's a noisy little dude in the sack.
莱纳德在床上是个吵死人的小混蛋
- Every night. - Really?
-夜夜笙歌  -真的吗
Even during allergy season, when he has to alternate
即使在接吻和喘气都得轮流干的
between kissing and breathing?
过敏季节也这样吗
It's my sister. Can we not talk about this anymore?
那是我妹妹  咱们就此打住行吗
Yeah. Sorry, sorry.
好  抱歉抱歉
Can I tell you a secret?
我能告诉你个秘密吗
Yeah.
行
I screwed up.
是我搞砸了
Leonard's a great guy.
莱纳德是个好人
Never should have broken up with him.
我不应该跟他分手的
Well, uh, to paraphrase Shakespeare:
我改编一下莎士比亚的话好了
（其实应该是来自Alfred Lord Tennyson）
"It's better to have loved and lost
"爱过  失去过"
（原话应该是 It's better to have loved and lost than never to have loved at all.）
"than to stay home every night
"总好过每晚在家"
and download increasingly shameful pornography."
"下载日益下流的黄色图片"
Ohh... you poor baby.
你个可怜的小家伙
What's wrong with me, Penny?
我这是什么毛病  佩妮
Nothing, nothing.
没病  没病
You know, if we weren't friends,
如果我们不是朋友
and you hadn't brought up that creepy pornography story,
如果你没提到那个恶心黄色图片小故事的话
I'd be on you like
我肯定会爬到你身上
the speed of light squared on matter to make energy.
以光速平方进出身体  产生能量
Hey, you totally got that right!
哇  你居然完全懂啊
"E=mc2."
能量等于质量乘以光速的平方[爱因斯坦质能等价理论]
I listen.
我听着呢
I have no idea what it means, but I listen.
虽然不知道什么意思  但我听着呢
- To friendship. - To friendship.
-致友谊  -致友谊
Would you booze hounds please stop that infernal clinking?!
你们俩酒鬼能别发出那种讨人厌的碰杯声吗
And the answer was elephant!
还有  答案是大象
Leonard, sweetheart,
莱纳德  亲爱的
we're kissing, not eating hot soup.
我们是在接吻  不是在喝热汤
Sorry.
抱歉
That's my parents on video chat.
我父母要跟我视频通话
Go hide in the bedroom.
快躲进卧室里
Oh, come on!
拜托
Why don't we just tell them that we're dating?
为什么不直接告诉他们  我们在约会呢
Oh, we've been through this. It's not the time.
我们讨论过这个  现在还不是时候
When is the time?
那何时才是时候
I've got five brothers and sisters.
我有5个兄弟姐妹
One of them is bound to screw up real big,
肯定会有其中一个闯大祸
and then I'll tell my parents about you.
到时候我就向我父母介绍你
- Now, shoo. - Fine.
-现在快闪  -好吧
Hello, Mummy. Hello, Daddy.
你好  妈咪  你好  爹地
We heard there was a tornado in Kansas City.
我们听说堪萨斯城有龙卷风
Is that close to you?
那离你们近吗
No.
不近
Where is your brother?
你哥哥呢
Out with friends.
跟朋友出去玩了
I don't like it, a young girl alone in an apartment.
我不喜欢这样  一个年轻姑娘独自在家
I'll sleep so much better
等你下个月搬回来后
when you move back here next month.
我的睡眠质量肯定上升不少
You're moving back to India?!
你要搬回印度
Who's that?
谁在那儿
Oh, my God! There's someone in your apartment.
天啊  你屋子里有别人
Call the police in America!
快打电话给美国的警察
When were you going to tell me about this?
你打算什么时候告诉我这事
Oh, hello, Leonard.
你好啊  莱纳德
What a pleasant surprise!
真是个意外的惊喜啊
Mummy, Daddy, you remember Rajesh's friend Leonard.
妈咪爹地  你还记得拉杰的朋友莱纳德吧
I thought you said Rajesh was out with his friends.
我以为你说拉杰跟朋友出去玩了
He has many friends.
他有很多朋友  好不好
Rajesh has many friends?
拉杰居然有很多朋友
Why are you lying to us?
你为什么要对我们撒谎
She's lying because she doesn't want you to know
她撒谎是因为她不想告诉你们
- we're dating. - Leonard!
-我们在约会  -莱纳德
Well, what difference does it make?
现在还有什么区别吗
If you're moving back to India, we're obviously breaking up.
如果你回印度  我们肯定是要分手的
You know what? I don't want to deal with this right now.
那啥  我现在不想讨论这个问题
So...
所以说
Hot in India?
印度很热吧
Of course it is. It always is. It's India.
当然是  一直是  这可是印度
Now, what do you have to say for yourself?
现在你有什么好说的
That is a beautiful tapestry.
你们家的挂毯真漂亮
Oh, God.
天啊
Oh, God!
上帝啊
Okay, look.
你给我听着
This never happened.
这事从没发生过
Do you understand me?
明白吗
Really?! Still can't talk to me?
搞毛啊  都这样了还不敢跟姐说话
What are you doing here?
你在这儿干嘛
What?
什么
I said, what are you doing here?
我问  你在这儿干嘛
I live here.
我住这儿
I have paperwork that says differently.
我的文件可不是这么说的
Priya's going back to India.
普丽娅要回印度了
Irrelevant.
这是两码事
Rajesh and I have a good thing going
拉杰和我相处得很融洽
and you're not going to ruin it.
你不能就这么毁掉它
What are you doing here?
你来这儿干嘛
I've been up all night.
我一宿没睡
- I had a fight with Bernadette. - Why?
-我跟贝纳黛特吵了一架  -为什么
She gave me a beautiful watch.
她送了我一块漂亮的手表
Leonard, do you understand this?
莱纳德  你懂他在说啥吗
Yes.
我懂
Talk to him.
跟他说去
Damn.
完了
What's going on?
这是怎么回事
It's-it's not what it looks like.
反正不是你们看上去的那样
What does it look like?
那到底看上去像怎么样